接下来，我们将看一下惯性项。这是加速所需的扭矩
Next, we are going to look at the inertia term. That's the torque required to accelerate
手臂的关节。这就是这个术语。所以，我们将跨越其他两个。
the joints of the arm. That's this term here. So, we'll cross the other two out.
现在，我将计算机器人的惯性矩阵，这是另一种方法
Now, I'm going to compute the inertia matrix of our robot, and that's yet another method
在双链路机器人对象上，该方法被称为“惯性”和参数
on the two-link robot object, and the method is called "inertia" and the arguments to that
是机器人Q1和Q2的关节角度。而且，这里我们有2x2的惯性矩阵
are the joint angles of the robot Q1 and Q2. And, here we have the 2x2 inertia matrix of
我们的机器人再一次，我们可以看到它是运动学和动力学参数的函数
our robot. Once again, we can see that it is a function of kinematic and dynamic parameters
一个机器人，它也是机器人配置的功能，我们可以看到
of a robot, and it's also a function of the configuration of the robot, and we can see
Q2的正弦和余弦出现在这个表达式中。这是我们两个链接的惯性矩阵
sine and cosine of Q2 appearing in this expression. Here is the inertia matrix for our two link
机器人机械手。它是一个2x2矩阵，它是一个对称矩阵;这意味着这一点
robot manipulator. It's a 2x2 matrix and it's a symmetric matrix; and that means that this
这里的术语与此术语相同。而且，我们可以看到惯性矩阵是完全的
term here is equal to this term here. And, we can see that the inertia matrix is quite
复杂而且不是常数。我们可以看到这个矩阵中的元素
complex and it is not constant. We can see that the elements in this matrix
是关节角度Q2的函数，以及机器人连杆的质量，运动学
are functions of the joint angles Q2, as well as the masses of the robot link, the kinematic
参数A1和A2，以及质心的位置，C2。我们可以把它写进来
parameters A1 and A2, and the position of the centre of mass, C2. We can write it in
简化形式，我们在主对角线上只有三个独特的元素，I11，I22，
simplified form where we have just three unique elements, I11, I22 on the principal diagonal,
和I12和I21在对角线上。而且，正如我刚才提到的，矩阵是对称的
and I12 and I21 on the opposite diagonal. And, as I just mentioned, the matrix is symmetric
所以I12等于I21。扭矩矢量作用于机器人的
so I12 equals I21. The vector of torques acting on the robot's
惯性矩阵乘以关节加速度矢量给出关节。现在，
joints are given by the inertia matrix multiplied by the vector of joint accelerations. Now,
我们可以扩展它，我们现在可以突出显示对角线上的两个术语。
we can expand that out, and we can highlight now the two terms on the diagonal.
在之前的讲座中，当我们考虑机器人关节控制时，生活很简单。我们有
In the previous lecture when we considered robot joint control, life was simple. We had
电动机施加在关节上的扭矩与加速度之间的关系
a relationship between the torque that the motor applies to a joint, the acceleration
一个关节和该关节的惯性。现在，我们可以看到事情并不完全
of a joint and the inertia of that joint. Now, we can see that things are not quite
如此直截了当我们可以看到扭矩1和扭矩之间存在关系
so straightforward. We can see that there is a relationship between torque 1 and the
关节1的加速就像我们在更简单的情况下一样。但我们现在也有这些
acceleration of joint 1 just like we had in the simpler case. But we now also have these
干扰扭矩。这意味着作用在接头1上的扭矩不仅归因于加速度
disturbance torques. That means that the torque acting on joint 1 is due not just to the acceleration
关节1，也是关节2的加速度。
of joint 1, but also to the acceleration of joint 2.
想象一下，关节1是静止的。它没有加速。联合控制是
Imagine for a moment that joint 1 is stationary. It's non-accelerating. The joint control is
试图保持静止。如果第2关节开始加速，它将会发挥作用
trying to keep it stationary. If joint number 2 starts to accelerate, it's going to exert
关节1号上的扭矩，关节1电机控制器必须处理
a torque on joint number 1, which the joint 1 motor controller is going to have to deal
用。它将不得不提出一些额外的扭矩，将其应用于电机停止
with. It's going to have to come up with some extra torque, apply it to the motor to stop
由于关节2的影响，关节1移动。我们将计算它的惯性
joint 1 moving, due to the influence of joint 2. We're going to compute the inertia of this
机器人数字。我们将使用惯性方法并计算它
robot numerically. We're going to use the inertia method and going to compute it for
关节角度零，零，这是惯性矩阵，我们可以看到它是对称的。
joint angle zero, zero, and this is the inertia matrix and we can see that it is symmetric.
这里的元素在这里等于这个元素。而且，只是为了提醒自己的配置
This element here equals this element here. And, just to remind ourselves of the configuration
这个机器人，我们将绘制它。它就是。所以，这是带有手臂的机器人
of this robot, we are going to plot it. There it is. So, this is the robot with its arm
完全伸出来。现在，我们可以做的是更改配置。所以，我要走了
fully outstretched. Now, what we can do is to change the configuration. So, I'm going
将机器人置于第二关节角度为90度的配置中。所以，
to put the robot in to a configuration where the second joint angle is 90 degrees. So,
现在机器人看起来像这样。而且，我可以计算这个新配置的惯性，
now the robot looks like this. And, I can compute the inertia for this new configuration,
0pi/2。并且，我们可以看到惯性矩阵的某些元素已经改变。
0 pi/2. And, we can see that some elements of the inertia matrix have changed.
事实上，他们已经减少了。并且，这里的元素，这是看到的惯性
In fact, they have been reduced. And, this element here, which is the inertia seen by
关节1减少了。那是因为关节2的质心现在更接近了
joint 1 is reduced. And that is because the centre of mass of joint 2 is now closer to
关节的旋转轴1.现在，我可以更进一步。我们来看看是什么
the rotational axis of joint 1. Now, I can bring that in even further. Let's see what
如果我将机器人放入第一个角度为0和第二个角度的配置中，看起来就好像
it looks like if I put the robot in to a configuration where the first angle is 0, and the second
关节角度等于pi或180度，手臂向后折叠，这样
joint angle is equal to pi or 180 degrees and the arm is folded back on itself, which
实际上可能不是物理上可能的，但让我们一起工作。
may not actually be physically possible, but let's work with that.
现在，我可以看一下这种配置中的惯性，看看它进一步减少了。那是
Now, I can look at the inertia in this configuration and see that it is even further reduced. That's
因为机器人的所有质量都尽可能接近旋转轴
because all the mass of the robot is as close as it possibly can get to the rotational axis
因此，如果我崩溃了这个数字，那么我们可以看到的是逐步的
of joint 1. So, if I collapse that figure, then what we can see is progressively the
随着我们增加关节，惯性矩阵中元素的大小变得越来越小
magnitude of the elements in the inertia matrix become less and less as we increase joint
角度2.而且，这是我们将重新审视的主题
angle 2. And, this is a topic that we will revisit
不久。联合控制系统的问题，当它必须处理惯性时
shortly. The problem for a joint control system, when the inertia that it has to deal with
随机器人的配置而变化。
varies with the configuration of the robot.